How to use QR codes in the insurance and
investment industries?
The journey to conversion can be a long
or a short path for your clients. Of
course, the short path is preferable,
but you need the right tools for it.
Well, you can achieve this with QR codes
and more. So stay tuned and we'll show
you how to do it. But before we go on,
let's talk about what a QR code is. A QR
code is short for quick response code.
It's a matrix barcode that serves as a
key to unlocking data that leads to
virtually wherever you want it to be.
And there's two types of QR codes. You
have your static and your dynamic.
Static QR codes, they're fixed QR codes
and its contents cannot be edited.
Dynamic QR codes on the other hand,
they're the flexible type. Dynamic QR
codes are more beneficial for marketing
since you can set up a QR code tracking
system to track the number of scans when
the user scans, the location where they
scan it, and the user's device type. You
can generate QR codes for your URLs,
V-cards, PDF files, social media
accounts, and many more. What makes it
even better is that you can edit and
update your data anytime. Here are ways
that you can use QR codes for your
operations as an investment or insurance
company.
One,
marketing and lead generation.
Add more value to your marketing
materials and generate more leads by
putting a URL QR code in them. You can
put your QR code on posters or flyers
where it's easy for people to scan.
This will then direct them to your
conversion page where they can sign up
as a lead.
Embed a QR code with your website's URL
in seven easy steps. Step one, go to
qr-tiger.com.
Step two, choose the QR code solution
that you need. Step three, type in or
paste your link. Step four, choose
dynamic QR since it lets you edit and
track data as opposed to a static QR
code. The data then helps you create
smart campaigns for a more effective way
of marketing your products and services.
Step five, click generate QR code.
Step six, customize the look and feel of
your QR code.
Tip, make sure you are satisfied with
how your QR code looks because you won't
be able to edit it after clicking done
editing/download.
You can also choose a design from the
customizable templates below.
If you customize your own QR code
design, you can save it as a template by
ticking the save as template box.
Step seven, once you're done editing and
reviewing your data, click done
editing/download.
Tip, we suggest you download in SVG
format since it allows you to adjust
your QR code to different sizes without
affecting the image's quality.
Two,
networking. Physical business cards hold
a limited amount of information and
they're easy to forget.
A V-card QR code can help you create a
lasting impression and stand out from
everyone else. You can also put it on
your business card and give it away to
potential clients.
They can then easily scan your V-card QR
code with their smartphones and save
your contact details in just a few taps.
This is useful for when they want to
reach you or ask about the policies
you're selling. Not only will this give
you an edge, it also will put you on top
of their mind since they can quickly
reach you with just a scan and tap.
Educate and spread awareness. Another
effective way to increase conversions is
to educate prospects on the advantages
of investing and having an insurance
policy. The space in a pamphlet or a
poster can be limited. You can explain
more about a policy or a process when
you add a file QR code on your posters.
Scanning it will then lead to a PDF file
where your prospects can read some
guidelines or important information.
What makes it great is that clients can
read it comfortably on their phone
whenever they want to.
Four, presenting multimedia content. So
when showcasing your meaningful
advertisements, a TV or digital
billboard slot can get pricey and can be
up for only a short amount of time. But
when you use a video QR code, prospects
can watch your videos anytime on their
smartphones. You can lead people into
watching your videos from your print
ads.
Put up your QR code on posters,
magazines, or brochures and people will
be able to access your video anytime,
anywhere.
If you post other multimedia content on
different platforms, you can also use a
social media QR code for it. This will
help you link all your social media
accounts in just one landing page.
Prospects will not only watch your
content, they can also follow, share,
and interact with your posts.
Five, digitize services. Going digital
is a wise move since almost everyone
owns a smartphone. Having an app for
your services would be really beneficial
for both you and your clients. They will
have quick access to your services, get
notified on the latest updates, provide
feedback, and more. Make it easier for
your clients to download your app by
providing them an App Store QR code.
This is the fastest way for them to
download your app hassle-free. All they
have to do is scan your QR code, tap the
install button, and they're done. It's
that easy.
So, what are the five ways that you can
use QR codes to your advantage? One, for
marketing and lead generation. Two, for
networking. Three, to educate and spread
awareness. Four, to present multimedia
content. And five, for your digitized
services.
QR codes can be a very effective
marketing tool if you know how to use
them the right way. Don't worry. I'm
here to help you equip yourself with the
fundamentals that you need. Just click
the subscribe button and hit the
notification bell to be alerted on new
uploads in our channel. For more QR code
content, you can browse this channel's
videos or visit our blog website link in
the description box below. This has been
David. I'll see you in the next video.